<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Arnaud Peralta</title><link>https://arnaudperalta.com/</link><description>Recent content on Arnaud Peralta</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:59:17 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arnaudperalta.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Never use Docker Compose again for production</title><link>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/swarm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:59:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/swarm/</guid><description>Why using Docker Compose for production is bad? OK, that&amp;rsquo;s a bit misleading, it&amp;rsquo;s not THAT bad. With compose, you are defining your services with a simple YAML file and you can pull images from your registry. So, with a good integration and a correct deploy script, you can have a good experience with Docker Compose on production.
When I say, it&amp;rsquo;s bad, it&amp;rsquo;s because you are one command away from using Docker Swarm, a simple container orchestrator, defined for production usage.</description></item><item><title>I use the QWERTY layout, and everyone thinks I'm crazy</title><link>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/qwerty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:59:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/qwerty/</guid><description>Why I switched from AZERTY I&amp;rsquo;m a french, I have been using AZERTY since my young age. My phone, my computer keyboards, and my laptop has the AZERTY layout, but I changed this 2 years ago for the US QWERTY layout.
Most of my coworkers and friends think I&amp;rsquo;m a nerd and don&amp;rsquo;t understand the point of my change, but I will never go back again.
Disadvantages Here is the AZERTY layout :</description></item><item><title>GNU Make, you known it, now use it !</title><link>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/makefile/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:59:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/makefile/</guid><description>Here is a scenario that you have probably already experienced: you intervene on a new project and your first reflex is to read the README file to understand what is going on, then starting your development. You begin to realize that this README is no longer very up-to-date and that some versions have changed. You advance by trial and error then give up by asking for help from another developer to finish your installation.</description></item><item><title>WSL + X Server + i3 : The good way to develop on Windows.</title><link>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/wsl_i3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 23:27:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/wsl_i3/</guid><description>During my university years, I searched a good way to work as a developper when I&amp;rsquo;m forced to work on Windows.
At the very beginning, I started the web developpment with WampServer and upgraded to WSL2 with a Ubuntu distribution. However, I was not really satisfied as my work environnment was not fully on GNU/Linux.
As a web developper, I always found out that working on a different OS than the deployment server was very silly.</description></item></channel></rss>