<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Arnaud Peralta's Blog</title><link>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Arnaud Peralta's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.149.1</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arnaudperalta.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Life-sentenced subscriptions</title><link>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/life_sentenced_subscriptions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/life_sentenced_subscriptions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Most people around me are either subscribing to or are part of a cloud storage plan. They usually pay each month around 4€ to keep their media, phone backups, passwords and messages saved in the cloud. From a bigger perspective, this is a great product that prevents people from owning physical hardware that could be stolen or corrupted. The main issue I have with this offering is that people are willing to pay this product for their entire lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Living in a modern exile</title><link>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/modern_exile/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 23:16:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/modern_exile/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I decided to live free from social media and television news.
I wanted to eliminate sources of negative thoughts that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t act upon.
To this day, I&amp;rsquo;m still using LinkedIn that I find mandatory for career purposes without having the app on my phone.
In case I receive an important message, I will receive an email which is enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My connections to the outside world are intentionally limited: my wife, my workmates, my friends and Hacker News.
I know that I can count on them in a scenario I must acknowledge a very important news, and they &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; miss. I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to focus primarily on the tech world, as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t induce stress and provides information relevant to my job and my happiness.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Clearing the complexity : From Kubernetes to GCP Cloud Run</title><link>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/cloud_run/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 14:36:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/cloud_run/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m working in an IT service company, where I’ve been introduced to a new project last year.
The stack is not so boring, every services use Typescript with Hasura as a GraphQL API and PostgreSQL as a PaaS on GCP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the services were deployed across two environments on two different GKE clusters and a dedicated PostgreSQL instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These clusters had each two nodes. With the costs of the Kubernetes Engine, Compute Engine (with a total of 4 VMs where the nodes are installed), and Cloud SQL (2 PostgreSQL instances). The monthly billing was averaging 600 euros.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>You should not use Docker Compose for production</title><link>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/swarm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:59:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/swarm/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-using-docker-compose-for-production-is-bad"&gt;Why using Docker Compose for production is bad?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, that&amp;rsquo;s a bit misleading, it&amp;rsquo;s not THAT bad. With compose, you are defining your services with a simple YAML file and you can pull images from your registry.
So, with a good integration and a correct deploy script, you can have a good experience with Docker Compose on production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I say, it&amp;rsquo;s bad, it&amp;rsquo;s because you are one command away from using Docker Swarm, a simple container orchestrator, defined for production usage.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>About using QWERTY in France</title><link>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/qwerty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:59:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arnaudperalta.com/post/qwerty/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-i-switched-from-azerty"&gt;Why I switched from AZERTY&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m french, I have been using AZERTY since my young age. My phone, my computer keyboards, and my laptop has the AZERTY layout, but I changed this 2 years ago for the US QWERTY layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my coworkers and friends think I&amp;rsquo;m a nerd and don&amp;rsquo;t understand the point of my change, but I will never go back again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="disadvantages"&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the AZERTY layout :&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>